let's use integral calculus to find the
area under the curve Y equals X plus a
half
according to the fundamental theorem of
calculus the integral from 0 to n of X
plus a half DX is equal to the quantity
x squared over 2 plus X over 2 evaluated
at n and zero when we plug in n and 0
and subtract we get N squared over 2
plus n over 2 for the integral
on the other hand we can also compute
this integral by breaking up the region
into a bunch of different pieces like
this each of the pieces will then be the
definite integral from I minus 1 to I
under the function X plus a half so we
can add up all of these integrals
according to properties of integrals
once we do this we again get that each
integral is x squared over 2 plus X over
2 evaluated at the endpoints and thus we
get that the integral in question is
given by the sum from I equals 1 to n of
I
but now that we've computed the definite
integral in two separate ways we see
that the sum of the first n positive
integers is equal to N squared over two
plus n over 2.